Welcome to our enable weekend operations for merchant-fulfilled orders training.
Offers in the Amazon store come with a customer delivery promise.
This promise gives customers a date range in which they can expect an order to arrive.
Customers like to receive their orders as soon as possible, so it's important to promise them the
shortest delivery time possible.
The customer delivery promise is composed of handling time, transit time, and a small buffer in
case of the unexpected
like weather.
Today, we'll show you how to offer a better customer delivery promise by enabling weekend operations.
You may notice that non-business days make the handling time longer in the customer delivery promise.
Weekends and holidays are automatically counted as non-business days in the customer delivery promise.
So, if your handling time is normally two days and someone purchases your product on a Monday, you'll
be expected to ship by Wednesday.
But if someone purchases your product on Friday, two days that make up the weekend will be added
to your handling time, and you'll be expected to ship on Tuesday.
Depending on the customer's needs, that can be a long time for them to wait.
But if you're able to ship products on the weekend, you can make your listings more appealing to
those customers by enabling weekend operations.
From the Seller central home page, select the gear icon in the upper right to open the settings
menu and then select shipping settings.
Once you're on the shipping settings menu, select the general shipping settings tab.
Then scroll down to order fulfillment settings.
Select edit to the right to adjust these settings.
Scroll down to weekend Operations settings or select it from the menu on the left to edit your settings
for weekend operations.
Here, you can choose to have your packages picked up by shipping providers on either Saturday, Sunday,
or both.
If you enabled shipping settings automation or SSA on your shipping templates to automatically calculate
your delivery promise,
you'll also need to enable weekend operations for SSA-enabled products in the shipping region automation
section, which can be found below.
For more information on SSA, search for shipping settings automation in Seller University or on
Seller Central's help page.
Once you've chosen your desired settings, don't forget to save them using the button in the upper
right or your settings selections will be lost.
Now you know how to enable weekend operations for your merchant fulfilled orders.
With this setting enabled, your customer delivery promise can improve, making your products more
appealing to potential buyers,
especially those shopping at the end of the week.
Finally, remember that enabling weekend operations means more than just working on the weekends.
It sets the expectation that you'll ship packages on the weekend too.
So if you don't have a shipping provider that picks up packages on Saturday, don't set Saturday
as a pickup day in your general shipping settings.
This concludes our enable weekend operations for merchant fulfilled orders training.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.